I say the Chinese people "go abroad and love China more".
What did you take with you the first time you travelled abroad?
Why would you make it about [China's] politics and economy?
The Communist Party said we must
rely on the masses and mobilize the masses.
Can we bring out the power of the people?
We need both a close-up and a long shot
when we observe China, don't we?
The post-90s and post-95s are
the most confident generation in China.
"Vote by feet."
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
I said "go abroad and love China more"
because people where shaming China.
They were like "All the Chinese people want to emigrate."
And I said, "That's good. We will send them abroad."
"They are welcome to leave and emigrate, aren't they?"
OK, everyone's here.
Please remember your seat, everyone.
Here, I'll take a look.
This doesn't feel like a production meeting.
We got high talking about it.
I'd like to ask everyone what you would bring
if you could only bring one thing on a trip abroad.
Mobile payment.
I saw this yesterday that Sweden will claim
to be the first cashless country by 2035.
It got me thinking where China is at in 2035.
Can you imagine what I brought when I went to the UK
for the first time over a decade ago?
I brought pickled cabbage and bamboo shoots from my hometown.
My family gave me a handful of soil.
Soil from my hometown.
It was put in a small bag and packed at the bottom of my suitcase.
Personally speaking, if I go on a short trip abroad,
there's really nothing that I have to bring.
But for a long-term stay, I'd like to bring the
vibe or the small environment around me.
My family ties.
My parents, my partner, my children.
A small environment like this.
We know for a fact that many people in the past
had to give up their family when they worked abroad.
I remember watching a documentary called On The Road [侣行].
It's about a couple travelling around the world
and they experienced wars and so on.
There was one sentence that really touched me.
[We didn't know that] The world is not in peace
because we live in a peaceful country.
The Shanghai Police have to deal with all kinds of issues.
Not only public security and criminal cases,
but also trivial matters like opening a lock,
or rescuing a cat under a car.
We are so used to enjoying and recognizing [their service].
And we forgot that it's not like this everywhere in the world.
This also reminded me another premise.
When we go abroad,
you face, the color of your skin,
will become a label of you.
In China you can't experience the true meaning of racism.
If we take America as an example,
the propositions of some groups are absolutely politically correct.
But they say the Asian expats cannot even
attain a place in political correctness.
Whether it's Han people and the ethnic minorities,
or the Chinese people and foreigners,
we co-exist on an equal footing.
I have a friend from Taiwan who was dating a British guy.
But she got mad when he said "You don't look Chinese."
This is still quite common in Europe.
When they see well-mannered Asians,
Europeans might stereotypically ask if they are from Japan.
Yeah. "You don't look Chinese."
That would make me really uncomfortable.
They might not have any bad intentions.
They just don't know us well enough.
If every Chinese expat can take the
opportunity to interact with them,
and make the effort to show the changing image of China,
we will have more meaningful international exchanges.
With a rising economy, more Chinese people can afford to go abroad.
They will drive the cycles of communication and understanding.
In the beginning, we felt a sense of mission
because the world viewed us with biases.
And we gradually became more natural.
Just show them how I am.
And in the end we tell them this is China.
China is not a derogatory word.
They are able to view us objectively.
As media professionals, we know we must show
the close-up, the mid-shot, and the long shot of a place.
Going out is a long shot for us.
It's an important perspective to help us
understand the environment we are in.
The Chinese people are well-travelled.
I believe a lot of people feel the same way.
I'm afraid the audience will resonate too early.
They will be like "This is it."
And we finish the episode too soon.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Different views can be discussed and debated.
We are not at all afraid of competition.
China, be confident.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Hello everyone, welcome to China Now.
We are here to learn about China, position China, and understand China!
Standing next to me is our keynote speaker,
Professor Zhang Weiwei, Director of the
China Institute of Fudan University. Welcome!
There are many people in the audience today, including
our pre-production panel. Welcome everyone!
We will first listen to Professor Zhang's speech
and then he will have conversations with the audience.
Now, I will give the stage to Professor Zhang.
Thank you.
I gave a speech in 2014 titled "The Chinese, You Need to Be Confident".
It was made into a video by Guan Video.
The video probably gained over 100 million views online.
In the video, I told a story about giving a lecture
about China's Rise at a university in Shanghai.
In the Q&A segment, a young scholar asked me,
"Professor Zhang, you speech made me feel
the Chinese people are very happy about their lives."
"But there are so many people who want to emigrant."
"Can you tell them to stay?"
I said, "You're asking the right person."
"I know so many Chinese expats."
"It would be silly to tell them to stay.
I'd encourage them to go."
"I did a study which found Chinese people
to love China more after they went abroad."
"It's true. It's better than the Party's education."
"I have a conservative estimate that"
"over 70% loved China more after they went abroad."
"I have a tip for you if you'd like to move to New York."
"I'm probably as familiar with New York as with Shanghai."
"You can fly from Shanghai Pudong Airport or
Hongqiao Airport to any airport in New York."
"Now most flights go to Newark Airport."
"You will experience flying from a
first-world airport to a third-world airport."
Most of the America's infrastructure
was built in the 1950s and 1960s.
It can't compare with China's.
I also jokingly asked him to stay in Newark for a night.
I did that myself.
"See if you are brave enough to go out at night."
I have a friend who worked as a postdoc
at Rutgers New Jersey Medical School.
I asked him, "What's the best department of your school?"
He said, "I don't mean to scare you,
but it's the trauma care department."
If you have some basic knowledge of America,
you will know that this country is made up of
the third world, the second world, and the first world.
If you unfortunately fall into America's third world,
sorry, your life is likely to be miserable.
If you work hard like many Chinese students abroad
and enter the second world or the middle class,
you can ask whether their real wages
have increased in the past two decades,
whether their house has appreciated if they purchased one,
and whether they are confident about retirement in America.
I'm not saying everything in America is not good.
Many things in America are good.
But many public intellectuals are still fabricating
"America: a perfect world on the other shore".
That makes me "laugh my teeth off".
If I were asked to make a speech on this topic today,
I would say "Go abroad and love China More".
I estimated at least 80% of the Chinese
people abroad feel this way today,
an even larger proportion than in 2014.
A major reason is that the post-90s and post-95s
have joined the wave of going out.
Big data tells us that the post-90s and post-95s
are probably the most confident generation in China.
They have no memory of China's poverty.
They are also a generation on mobile phones.
Wherever they go to in the world,
they will find out China is the only country where everything can be done on a [smart] phone.
I remember giving a speech for
an institute in Shanghai about 4 years ago.
They were developing a long-term plan for the cultural
construction of Shanghai as an international metropolis.
They wanted my input because they heard
that I had been to over 100 countries.
I was happy to attend and asked them
to show me some previous studies.
They provided me two reports.
Long story short,
they reports found Shanghai was behind New York in what,
behind Paris in what,
and behind London in what.
I told them, "I have lived in these three cities myself,
and I don't feel that is exactly the case."
"In some areas, Shanghai has been doing better or much better."
In terms of infrastructure, Shanghai is
leading the other three cities overall.
It has surely surpassed New York.
It's comparable to and even better than London and Paris.
We can also compare median household net worth.
We have the data.
And average life expectancy, infant mortality rate, and so on.
We noticeably outperform New York.
And we can compare the same statistics with London and Paris.
Shanghai's social security is better
or much better than the three cities.
These are the important benchmarks.
I also suggested that when they plan for Shanghai or any city,
they should consider how the local people feel in general.
Right?
Especially their cultural preferences.
If we look at the world through the perspectives and
the cultural preferences of the Chinese people,
and compare with New York, London, and Paris,
it will allow us to make better plans.
One indicator they considered was the
number of restaurant per capita of a city,
which is the population divided by the number of restaurants.
A higher value is more desirable.
I suggested that they can also consider the
variety of restaurants as another dimension.
China would score much better with that considered.
This is one of our cultural preference.
We would often like to eat something different.
[hot pot]
"The food can never be too finely prepared."
[noodles]
[roasted duck]
We prefer the diversity in food.
We can't eat hot dogs and burgers all the time.
[shumai]
We'd be tired of that after a day or two.
We "go abroad and love China more"
firstly because of our taste buds.
This is really how you would feel when visit another country.
"The food here is 1000 years behind China."
The university students would always
complain about their canteens at school.
They would be picky about this and that.
And they become nostalgic when they go abroad.
"When could have the variety of food back home?"
China is a civilized state that is "a whole a hundred nations".
A slow integration of hundreds of nations.
Other countries can hardly compare to China in the richness of food.
I believe French cuisines are the best in Europe.
But any of our eight regional cuisines
surpass French cuisines in width and depth,
and richness and variety.
French cuisines only belong to the French nation
while ours were formed by hundreds of nations.
Another indicator I suggested they can consider is
the Chinese people prefer to have a private room when
they dine with family or friends in the restaurants.
For restaurants abroad, especially in the West,
private rooms are a luxury.
Probably 99% of the restaurants don't have any.
People normally eat in the hall.
So we can add our cultural preference to the comparative study
and consider the proportion of restaurants offering private rooms.
For a comparison between countries,
we should not only use western standards.
We must blend in Chinese elements.
"From getting rich to getting strong."
We are strong when we look at the world through the Chinese eye.
Can you meet our standards?
That's just an example.
It can be projected to other aspects of life.
The second cultural preference is the family culture.
The Chinese people make far more sacrifices
to their family than the average westerners.
In a discussion held by the Ministry of Culture,
an internal meeting about "Chinese movies going out".
An official in the international promotions of Chinese movies said
our movies had a hard time going out.
Why?
Because we only had Kungfu movies.
It seemed the foreign audience was not interested in anything else.
I said, "How's that possible?"
I remember watching a movie about 20 years ago in New York,
"The Joy Luck Club".
It was a simple story about 3-4
[immigrant] mothers and their daughters.
The movie was developed based on
their past experiences and new life.
An elderly American lady was sitting next to me in the theater.
She cried when she was watching the movie.
She told me it was like her memories of the 50s
and people were not like that any more.
Behind the movie was the ongoing disintegration of the
many western societies, especially the American society.
If we look at its social structure from a Chinese perspective,
it is more of less fragmenting.
For example, I found 2014 data that
traditional families accounted for only
19% of the American population.
Traditional families as in "parents + children"
and they only accounted for 19%.
The others were non-traditional families
including cohabitation of unmarried couples, childless couples, and LGBT.
And a not small proportion of "big children having kids"
with the father unknown.
Some studies found the crime rates are
linked to such families with absent fathers.
A movie about ordinary Chinese family life and
family bonds can reach the hearts of many foreigners.
The third is the neighborhood culture.
It's our everyday life.
Did anyone notice the first thing President Xi said
to the press after his inauguration was
"The Chinese people have so much love for life"?
"The people's pursuit of a better life is our quest."
We have so much enjoyment in our
everyday life and value that a lot.
The nongtangs [alleyways] in Shanghai,
or the hutongs [alleyways] in Beijing.
People playing chess or cards, having tea,
doing tai chi or other morning exercises,
square dancing in the evenings, and so on.
I see a lot of foreigners getting excited about square dance in China.
The fourth is the commerce culture.
Shanghai, in my opinion, has the highest
commercial convenience in the world.
There is a 24-hour store every 5 minutes of walk.
We also have shopping websites such as Taobao and JD.
China's number of daily delivered parcels exceed
the total of the other major countries.
This is a consumer revolution online and offline .
If you have lived in Europe or America,
especially Europe,
most stores either close or shorten their business hours on weekends.
We are not used to that as a cultural preference.
We expect the stores to be open to 9pm or 10pm
and open on the weekends.
This is a cultural difference.
Same with online shopping.
We usually expect to receive a parcel
on the same day or the next day.
But it usually takes one or more weeks abroad.
Our "hand choppers" [online shopaholics] are even counting by hours.
Related to e-commerce,
the fifth culture preference is the advancement of mobile Internet.
Everything can be done on a [smart] phone.
Booking hotels and flights,
chats and gaming,
business payments,
they are all conveniently integrated into WeChat.
No other country has achieved this before.
I saw data showing that China's mobile payment
now is 70 times that of the United States.
Perhaps more post-90s than older generations love
China more when they are abroad because of the mobile culture.
The rapid growth of our mobile Internet results from the Chinese culture.
This is a really big topic.
I can dedicate a speech to it in the future.
Briefly, it comes from our "circle culture".
Not the "circle culture" in a negative sense.
It's neutral.
Chinese people likes to be in a circle and
we can create a few chat groups a day.
It's easy to form a group in the Chinese culture.
Another important reason is the Chinese language,
according to my personal findings.
The Chinese characters are compact.
The Chinese language can provide way more
information on a small screen than western scripts.
This also gives us an edge.
I can talk about this another time.
The last thing I'd like to mention is the red culture
[relating to the lifestyles during communist revolutions].
I often say the people's republic was born out of wars.
The red culture is the spirit that supported us through
the wars and an important heritage.
One of my Taiwanese friends,
who was a senior scholar of the KMT,
told me he found that KMT lost the Chinese Civil War,
or what the CPC call the Liberation War,
he said this half jokingly,
because the CPC had red songs.
The KMT didn't have those.
He said the KMT songs were so dull,
both the anthem of the KMT and anthem of the Republic of China
when compared to "March of the Volunteers"
[anthem of the People's Republic of China].
The spirits behind them are different.
I lived in western countries for a long time where
I found that a lot of people were in low spirits.
Some of of students told me they had to take medicine to feel better.
I was thinking what about sending
them to sing the red songs in China.
Experience the mommunal lifestyle.
The songs inspired our entire nation to fight and strive.
It's a positive energy.
China's [development] mode is difficult to duplicate.
One important reason is that the people fought for the republic through wars.
We are able to say no to America.
Few countries can do that.
This is very important.
All the cultures around the world have their advantages.
All their differences are admirable.
Different cultures and civilizations need to learn from one another.
However, I feel that the Chinese people
have a few qualities contributing to the rise of China.
They are all cultural factor.
The first is diligence.
The Chinese people are the most hard-working.
In other countries, you can't even pay people to do what we do.
The second is our motivation as a nation.
We always search for the way to change our fate.
This is not a quality of many nations.
China's rise can be attributed to this quality and the culture.
The third is a cultural disfavor of violence.
We are a peaceful nation overall.
If you have lived in America, do you see people taking a walk after dinner?
They don't feel safe to.
In New York, for example, expect for the guarded
tourist sites such as Times Square and Broadway,
you wouldn't want to go out for a walk at night.
Same with Paris,
it's a nice city,
but recently the local Chinese expats say
"There are only two types of Chinese people in Paris."
"Either robbed or to be robbed."
If all the cities went into a power outage tonight,
Shanghai, London, Paris, and New York.
Without police intervention,
New York would surely be the worst.
Followed by London and then Paris.
Shanghai would probably be the best.
Shanghai or China's public security is the best among the world,
I don't really want to say "one of".
It's definitely among the first class in the world.
The sense of security not only
comes from the hard work of the police,
we used to be safe without the technologies and police capacity today.
I believe it's because of our respect for peace as a nation.
You can drive to any village in China and feel safe.
You can talk to the folks there and buy their produce.
Frankly speaking, it's a luxury for any county
or most countries today.
Security feels like oxygen.
You don't feel it when you have it.
But you feel how crucial it is when you suddenly lose it.
The more places you visit in the world,
the more you will love your country
and appreciate the ordinary cultural practices in your country.
How about I stop here for today?
Thank you, Professor Zhang. Have a seat.
I have a personal question.
We know that Prof. Zhang was the translator of
our national leaders when he was young,
including Comrade Deng Xiaoping.
Prof. Zhang visited other countries with them.
I'm not going to ask what you brought for an official visit.
But I'm really curious to know what you
brought on your first personal trip abroad.
Because we were talking about this in the production meeting.
Everyone was sharing about what the brought on their first trip abroad.
So I'd like to ask Prof. Zhang this question today.
- You asked about my first personal trip?
- Yes.
I can start with diplomatic visits.
It was very interesting. Our salary was very low at that time.
I was working at the translation department
of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
We had a room to borrow luggage and overcoats.
We needed to sign IOUs.
Yeah, everything was borrowed.
- Like uniforms?
- Yes.
My first visit was to Thailand.
I was translating for a UN meeting.
I had never gone abroad before,
and I did lots of research and bought books [about Thailand].
I was very curious, and found
Thailand was so advanced after we arrived.
I felt it was 20 years ahead of Shanghai.
You didn't answer the question.
Books?
It was quite long ago for Professor Zhang to remember the details.
I have a question that many people would challenge.
"Go abroad and love China more" because we miss home naturally.
Why would you make it about politics and economy.
Is that far-fetched?
The context for that statement was the
west and pro-western public intellectuals
were attacking the PRC.
They said, "Your system will fail."
"Everyone wanted to leave."
"There's one wave after another in the emigration tide."
I asked, "Where is the data?"
No data was supporting their statement.
So I said "go abroad and love China more".
I encourage them to leave, even in organized groups.
Get a deal with America and send them out.
If you calculate the immigrant populations of major immigration countries,
the U.S. used to be the largest but now it's not truly
welcoming immigrants under Trump,
and Canada and Australia which have much smaller populations.
If we count the three countries all together,
how many immigrants do they receive every year?
Half a million?
And if all the immigrants were all from China,
that's still a small number.
Suzhou City itself has 10 million people.
- If we look at the proportions ...
- Our one community has that many people.
Yes, we used to think it was subjective.
But the data in the last 2 years shows over 80%
of the Chinese students abroad chose to come back.
An example is the movie "American Dreams in China".
[based on a real story]
Three college friends wanted to go to America.
But the one that spoke the best English couldn't go.
And it turned out that the one who
stayed in China had the highest career achievements.
There's this English expression, "vote by feet".
The west would alway say the Chinese people "voted by feet"
and lest their county.
I told them they could look at our compatriots in Taiwan.
Four years ago, a conservative estimate of 1.5 million
students from Taiwan chose to stay in Chinese mainland.
Do we have an updated number?
Over 2 million.
If you politicalize this, it is their "vote by feet".
The latests data shows that over 50% of the
young people want to study or work in mainland.
Young people in Taiwan.
That's a high proportion.
I remember a British documentary about
the lives of illegal immigrants in the UK.
A lot of them applied for political asylum in order to stay.
They fabricated all kinds of reasons.
Later on, the British immigration officers
got tired hearing the same statements.
A lot of the immigrants were from
Fujian Province to the UK and the US.
Now if we visit Pingtan, Changle, and Fuqing,
no one would want to emigrate illegale.
And many of the previous emigrates have come back.
China's growth can be seen from this kind of dark aspect.
If we recall the advertisements for
phones or software over 10 years ago,
we had futuristic scenes where there were cars flying
and a touch-screen device in your hand
with an integrated platform for everything.
China has taken advantage of the growth of mobile phone,
and our special reality of a large population and the love for life.
We have already implemented that.
But we didn't expect how fast this could be done.
What do our audience think about "go abroad and love China more"?
I look forward to the discussions.
Please throw your questions at Prof. Zhang.
Different views can be discussed and debated.
We are not at all afraid of competition.
China, be confident.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
I say the Chinese people "go abroad and love China more".
What did you take with you the first time you travelled abroad?
Why would you make it about politics and economy?
The Communist Party said we must
rely on the masses and mobilize the masses.
Can we bring out the power of the people?
We need both a close-up and a long shot
when we observe China, don't we?
The post-90s and post-95s are
the most confident generation in China.
"Vote by feet."
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
All sharp questions are welcome.
Please raise your hand and let me know.
Hello, Professor Zhang.
I would like to ask a question about our cultural output.
Although China has a strong economic
or political influence in the world,
our culture does not seem to have
synchronously grown in influence.
I wonder if we've been giving low priority to cultural exports.
I'm an engineer but I love China's traditional culture.
I believe our cultural exports should be more specific,
more operable, and more practical.
For example, acupuncture in traditional Chinese medicine.
As far as I know, at least 44 states in
the U.S. have legalized acupuncture.
I understand your question.
I'd like to ask what your specialization is as an engineer.
Networking.
A networking engineer interested in cultural issues.
And he particularly talked about acupuncture.
I am a fan of our traditional culture, so I follow the news.
I think going global is the general trend for Chinese culture.
Any country's rise in history is a rise of their culture.
This is "supply and demand".
When there is a huge demand, the supply should keep up.
The demand has been increasing.
And we do have room for improvement on the supply side.
Not only the simple things,
although they are necessary,
such as the cultural symbols: cheongsam, tea, and so on.
The key is to reveal the ideas behind them.
For example, the Chinese people cherish peace.
It will be contagious if we make it a cultural symbol.
For something to have a global impact,
it must have universal significance.
It will have greater penetration if everyone thinks it's good.
We can learn from the West.
A lot of the "worshippers of the West"
started as the admirers of their cultures.
If they have a "high-end culture" or something like that,
they spend lots of time on the cultural exports
from packaging design to the product itself
to make you feel it is an elegant culture.
Our culture has a "commoner" nature.
We can draw anything high-end from other countries and localize it.
The court dance has become our square dance.
The staff has been simplified to numbered musical notation.
Our culture is related to the socialist commoner nature.
So I think our next focus is high culture,
including high-end cultural products.
Other countries will spend a lot to buy our cultural products.
I believe this day will come.
Our friends care about how to make our culture better understood.
Things with practical utility will be easier to understand.
If you just show them a video,
it still might take them a while to understand.
They cannot directly relate to our culture.
But the examples you gave, acupuncture or cheongsam,
and if you remember the the mosquito nets that
the Chinese athletes brought abroad to the Olympics.
There's also scraping and cupping.
They all feel that these traditional things are simple and useful.
I like how Prof. Zhang said we need to let them
know the Chinese culture behind the things.
We must make sure the stories are understood.
All right, does someone else have a question?
Yes please.
In recent years, we can feel China's growth
and the growth of national confidence.
However, with the GDP gradually declining in recent
years, and a potential population crisis we will face,
I'd like to ask Prof. Zhang,
what do you think about the contradiction between the
two and the relationship and the concerns behind it?
A very sharp question!
I'd like to ask what you're specialized in.
I studied medical engineering and now
I am working in the medical industry.
I had a discussion with an expert who studies population.
He was relatively optimistic.
Aging will grow the "silver hair industry",
which is a huge opportunity.
He also suggested something that our female friends would disagree.
He suggested the retirement age for
women was low and should be raised.
So I'd have to retire later?
But I'm not that concerned about this issue.
About having children, the ever constant topic in many
Chinese TV series is the relationship between mother and wife.
"Are you pregnant?"
"Why don't you want a child?"
"Why are you still not pregnant?"
I thought urban-based dramas are about a
man's mother, wife, and sister
were probably only popular with the Chinese people.
That didn't turn out to be true.
We Love You, Mr. Jin was translated into Burmese.
A Beautiful Daughter-in-law Era was translated into more languages.
President Xi Jinping even talked about it when he visited Africa
because it was so popular in East Africa.
However, I think we really need to pay
more attention to the population problem.
The birth rate is very low now.
I'd like to take this opportunity to call on the government
to further open up the restrictions.
Have however many you want.
Yes, not the two-children policy.
As many as you want.
And we need to take some incentives.
I'd like to ask this friend, do you have a child?
I do.
Will you have a second child?
I have to think about it.
I encourage you to have a second child and a third child.
When we only have one child, we pay too much
attention to them and pressure on them.
Our generation was raised like the "free range lambs".
The probability of success is the same, I'm telling you.
How many "lambs" did you parents have?
- Six including myself.
- Six!
A big family. That's nice.
- Where do you come in your family?
- The sixth.
We have to stop asking him personal questions.
Professor Zhang, moving back to the question.
Our friend asked 2 questions actually.
The other one is the decline in the GDP growth rate.
It is a trend for the GDP growth rate to slow down
because the size of China’s economy is now very large.
If I did not calculate wrong, if China’s GDP growth rate
remains at 6.5% — the current level,
we create the GDP of the UK every three years.
With such a big economy, we can let it slow down naturally
and adjust the economic structure.
There is a solution, but we must take measures.
Solvable but action required.
Okay, anyone else?
Yes.
I have a question about China's grassroots governance.
I was born in a rural area
so I have experienced a lot of formalism and
bureaucracy in the grassroots governance.
Can we adopt a voting and scoring system
to partially replace the frequent top-down inspections and assessments?
Professor Zhang, what's your opinion on this?
What are the difficulties in its implementation?
Different views can be discussed and debated.
We are not at all afraid of competition.
China, be confident.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
I say the Chinese people "go abroad and love China more".
What did you take with you the first time you travelled abroad?
Why would you make it about politics and economy?
The Communist Party said we must
rely on the masses and mobilize the masses.
Can we bring out the power of the people?
We need both a close-up and a long shot
when we observe China, don't we?
The post-90s and post-95s are
the most confident generation in China.
"Vote by feet."
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
I have a question about China's grassroots governance.
I was born in a rural area
so I have experienced a lot of formalism and
bureaucracy in the grassroots governance.
Can we adopt a voting and scoring system
to partially replace the frequent top-down inspections and assessments?
Professor Zhang, what's your opinion on this?
What are the difficulties in its implementation?
Did you observe this in your daily life?
Were there frequent inspections from the
upper governments to your hometown?
I saw on banyuetan.org that there is a lot of
anomalies in China's grassroots governance.
One of them is the top-down inspections being too frequent.
They might even receive a few groups of inspectors a day.
They have to deal with one after another.
Their actual work cannot get done.
Yes, and they make inspections just as a matter of form.
The Communist Party said we must
rely on the masses and mobilize the masses.
Can we bring out the power of the people?
Let the people score [the officials].
From my research, an important consideration of President Xi is to
re-organize the grassroots organizations,
which have become too slack.
So they can better serve the grassroots communities.
But the phenomenon of formality that
you mentioned has been emerging.
Various tasks are pressed down,
and various forms are to be filled.
A grassroots government is like
"a needle under a thousand threads".
They are under a lot of stress.
This problem needs to be solved.
In fact, I think we can make full use of our traditional resources.
I surveyed some rural areas in Shandong Province.
They actually still... I forgot their names.
They still have "associations of seniors" or something similar
which are like our historical village governors.
The well-respected seniors in the village
form an organization to resolve conflicts.
They are no worse than the courts in handling many problems.
That's an example I can think of.
We have many inventions at the grass-roots level.
For example, the River Chief System.
A person is responsible for the a section of a river.
This is an important regulation in environmental management
that was pioneered at the grassroots level.
There is the grassroots formalism that you mentioned.
And there are also good examples at the grassroots level.
That's what's interesting about China.
We have so many problems on the one hand.
And on the other hand, we are coming up with different solutions.
And I like the solution you suggested a lot.
Instead of top-down inspections,
we can take a bottom-up approach such as opinion polls.
We can purchase a third-party service to do that.
We can immediately see how the officials perform.
I hope more people will hear about your suggestion and adopt it.
Thanks for the question. Anything you want to add?
I remember Professor Zhang often said that
China's selection-election system is better
than the western election-only system.
But I find that in our selection-election system,
the masses have not been fully mobilized.
Mobilizing the masses will "add wings to a tiger".
It will improve the systems such as
official appointments and dismissals.
The difficulty lies in how to mobilize
the masses to participate in selection and election.
There are also pilots and many successful cases.
For example, some forms of opinion polls were
conducted during the selection process.
The general practice is not always to select the top scorer.
They might just be trying to please
everyone but not doing a lot of work.
The low scorers will definitely be out.
We might be selecting from a layer.
It's important that we have this as a
factor for reference in the selection.
That will incorporate your suggestion into the system.
- Thank you, Professor.
- Thank you for the question.
I'd also like to ask Prof. Zhang.
The topic of this episode is "go abroad and love China more."
Some of our friends asked their questions
looking at China from a distance.
But the last question was about grassroots China.
We need both a close-up and a long shot
when we observe China, don't we?
We do.
I really believe what Deng Xiaoping siad,
I heard him saying this personally,
"A soldier who has heard gunfire is completely
different from a soldier who has not."
"Read thousands of books and travel thousands of miles."
[from an essay by Dong Qichang, Ming Dynasty]
That's how we "acquire knowledge with our feet".
Ultimately, this is "seeking truth from facts".
This is good practice for gaining knowledge, for
political research, and for decision making.
Combine the macro and the micro.
Chairman Mao said "a typical survey is like dissecting a sparrow".
I attended a forum in my hometown.
My old friends and the village folks would not lie to me.
All these maxims make sense.
Whether we open our eyes and go abroad to see the world,
or look at grassroots governance at home,
we are trying to learn about China
and understand China through our observations.
This is the end of this episode.
Let's give another round of applause for Prof. Zhang.
I'd like to thank all of our friends in the audience.
We'll see you again to learn about China,
understand China, and position China!
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组